Thank you, Detective
Any change?
Nothing since you left.
She seems to be looking for something.
Camera?
She has a nice ass.
Stay focused on the mission.
Keep an eye on her, but don't get too close.
- Good morning
What can I get for you?
Tea with milk and fresh orange juice-
-and a croissant with butter, I've already attended to it.
- Thank you
- No problem.
- Do you have a visual?
- I've got visual, she's drinking her tea.
- Say again?
- She's drinking her tea!
- Can I get you a tea, sir?
- No, no thank you.
- Good morning, sir
- Good morning
- I'm looking for Elise Ward
- Ward, the lady (pointing)
Okay, thanks
- Good morning, Elise Ward?
- Yes, that's me.
I have a letter for you
She's talking to someone
A delivery boy
Scotland Yard, London
Yes?
She's at the usual cafe, she's speaking with a man,
it looks like a messenger...
But you said to call if anything changed in her routine
Stay on his face.  His face!
- Do you think it's Alexander Pierce?
- I think everybody's Pierce.
No, it's okay.
It is a gift, you can keep it.
Thank you
- Here you go, goodbye.
- Goodbye.
Get him.
Alright, grab him.
Let's move.
Sir, sir! Sir, we are police.
- What did I do?
- You're under arrest
- You're coming with us.
- What did I do? - Shh!
What are you arresting me for?
"Elise, you have no reason to trust me any more..."
"But give me a chance to explain myself"
"I know the police are watching you, we have to throw them off the trail"
"Board the 8:22 at the Gare De Lyon"
"Pick someone my height and build, and make them believe it is me"
"Burn this letter."
"It is important you follow my instructions precisely.
I love you, Alexander"
It's from him.
Save that letter, go in now.
Save that letter!
Go, now!
- No, stop! Police!
- What happened?
Well?
The letter is burned to shit.
Don't fucking touch it.
Collect the ashes, take them to the van.
I'll send you someone.
The road's too narrow, we have to go around.  Quick!
Turn right!
Quick, go!
Let's go
Police, make way!
Damn!
Scotland Yard
Wednesday meeting.
So, Alexander Pierce has a new face
Just as you suspected
I'd have thought it must've taken quite a lot of the
money he stole from Reginald Shaw
To finance this transformation
Ahmed Toubali, bicycle courier of Algerian descent
Not only has Pierce acquired a wife, and a child...
He is also 4 inches shorter than the used to be.
That must have been a big item of expenditure?
Congratulations Acheson,
You have indeed cracked this case.
Sir, this morning she recieved a note...
and we have strong reason to believe -
Alexander Pierce has 744 million in illegal assets
That given he is a British Subject, we might seize.
This operation so far has cost me
eight million pounds.
If I thought there were more than a one in a hundred
chance you could be successful...
It would be rational for me to continue this operation...
I do not.
... that's an amendment... yes...
Thank you, sir
8:22
- Sir, the projection for the faces you asked for
- Not now
"8:22 Lyon"
Are they meeting in Lyon at eight twenty-two?
- Gare de Lyon, perhaps?
- Gare de Lyon...
That's it, Gare De Lyon!
The train station, she's getting on a 8:22 train.
Go!
"Board the 8:22 at the Gare De Lyon"
"Pick someone my height and build, and make them believe it is me"
- I'm sorry
- What for?
Do you mind me smoking?
It's not a real cigarette.
- What?
- It's electronic
It delivers the same amount of nicotine, but the smoke is water vapor.
Yeah, watch! (puffs)
LED light
That's somewhat disappointing.
Would you rather have me smoking for real?
No, I would rather you be a man who did exactly as he pleased.
- I'm Elise
- I'm Frank
- That's a terrible name
- (laughs) Yeah, that's the only one I've got.
- Maybe we can find you another...
- Okay
- You're British  - Mmm
- I'm American  - Hmm
What brings you to Venice?
You read spy novels.
I am a mysterious woman on a train..
You tell me what my story is.
Okay...
I think you would be a diplomat attach?
Or maybe a girl from East Germany
whose father's been kidnapped
And they're blackmailing you into stealing something for them...
Probably microfilm, there's usually microfilm involved.
- What awaits me?
- Trouble, certainly
- Danger?
- Oh, yeah.
You'll most likely be shot at in less than two chapters!
Is there a man in my life?
... have to wait and see.
- Invite me to dinner Frank
- What?
- Would you like to have the dinner?
- Women don't like questions
- Join me for dinner
- Too demanding
- Join me for dinner?
- Another question
I'm having dinner...
If you'd care to join me
Musician?
Bartender?
I give up.
Math, I teach maths.
I would not have guessed that.
I'd imagine you're a cool math teacher, though?
Still a math teacher.
- Can I take your picture?
- Sure
Urgent Message From:
Unit 17 To: John Acheson
- Could this be Pierce?
- We're still working on that
Well, I only have the sketches to go by, so...
Ectomorpheus, same basic phenotype
- Bottom line, could be him
- I knew we couldn't leave her
Run a worldwide blind check on that face,
Bet you ten quid there's no match
Okay, but what case number do you want to book it under?
- Just run it
- Do you really think it's Pierce?
Run it.
Get me Italian Interpol.
I have a strange feeling that those two people
over there are watching us
Do you know something?
I think you're right
Really?
You're paranoid, math teacher
Memorize this face
The train arrives in 10 minutes
Stop him when he descends.
So, what are you doing all alone in the city of lovers?
Is there no one in your life?
- There was.
- What happened?
- She left me.
- I'm sorry to hear that, Frank
"Arrival at train station Venicia Santa Lucia in 10 minutes.
End of the line"
Guess I should go get my suitcase and stuff.
- Goodbye
- Goodbye, thank you.
Oh shit.
- Sir
- Wait
"Pick someone my height and build"
"And make them believe it's me"
We did get an exact match
He's a math teacher at Madson Community College
Frank Tupelo
Lost his wife in a car crash three years ago
He's a tourist
Thank you
Get me Italian Interpol
Yes?
Received
Abort.  We go back to HQ quickly.
On the other side.
- What are you doing?
- The Internet Fraud Report
So, this is what Alexander Pierce looks like?
It's above your clearance.
Get back to your work.
He's fluttering his eyelids like a girl, that's his tell.
Go all in.
Damn.
Yes?
I have a piece of information for Mr. Shaw
It's concerning Alexander Pierce
Alexander Pierce has just arrived in Venice
With her.
- Aleri.
- Sir
- Change of course, Venice
- Yes, sir
Now what do I own in Venice?
Hi
- Do you want to come with me?
- What?
Oh yeah, sure, I mean, I-I could use a lift, yeah.
Thank you very - that's very kind.
Welcome to Venice, Madam
Bags.
Thank you
Oh, uh, my bags!
Are you coming?
Thank you (speaking spanish)
Hello, Welcome to Hotel Danieri, Madam
Elise Clifton-Ward, and husband
We have arranged for you a wonderful suite...
with bathroom and with...
- May I have your documents, please?
- Yes
Thank you
It will be my pleasure to show you up personally.
Please, this way.
Thank you
- Enjoy your stay, sir
- Thank you
Everything was arranged
according to the precise instructions.
I very much hope you will not be disappointed.
We are entering the Doches Suite
A room that has been a home away from home for
Marcel Proust and Honor?de Balzac
- Have a nice day, sir
- Thank you
Make yourself at home
This really is a very nice hotel, isn't it?
They think of everything, don't they?
I know he will be with her.
They'll be staying at one of the grand hotels.
The Pretty, The Regina, The Danieli.
I want you to keep a watch on all of them.
You can kill the girl, but you can't kill him.
Not until I have my money, that is.
- Is that clear?
- Yes, sir - Let's go.
- You're ravenous.
- Do you mean ravishing?
...I do.
- You're ravenous
- I am.
Come on!
- The, um, Skambian champagne risotto, please.
- Excellent choice, excellent.
He didn't say that to me
Did he not like my choice?
Your choice was excellent.
Who is he?
Hotels don't give gifts like that, do they?
- He's someone they used to be very important to me
- Used to?
Are you meeting him in Venice?
I hope so.
- Part of me hopes I don't
- Why?
Because I don't like being told what to do.
I don't like being "summoned".
But it felt even worse not
hearing from him for two years.
It's the Roman god, Janus.
My mother gave it to me when I was little.
She wanted it to teach me that people have two sides;
a good side, a bad side...
Past and future
And that we must embrace both in someone we love.
And I tried...
What's he like?
He's... different from anybody I know.
Different's good.
Where I come from the highest compliment...
that you can offer a person...
Is to say that they're down to earth...
Grounded.
I hate it.  Drives me nutso.
Would you like another Americano?
I don't know, would I?
It really was a very nice restaurant, wasn't it?
Oh.  Very nice wine.
I'm making us a nice little drink.
Which is very nice of me, isn't it?
Thank you
Were those flowers here when we checked in?
It is an invitation to a Ball, two nights from now.
You've been "summoned"
It appears I have.
May I pay you a compliment?
Another question you need never ask.
You are the least down to earth person I've ever met.
It's been a long day.
I do hope the couch will be comfortable.
Good night
Sorry, sir. Good morning.
My name is Guido, your waiter.
I'm Frank.  What's this?
It's your breakfast, sir.
- I didn't order any.
- The lady ordered it for you, when she left
When she left?
Have a nice day, sir.
- Hi.
- Alexander let's go see an old friend
- I'm not sure he's Pierce
- The boss warned us about this
Get him!
- Hello, please help
- Hello, sir
Hello, I'm in need of help there are two
men trying to break down the door
I see, what kind of problem do you have with the door, sir?
No, no, no, there are two men with guns trying to break in!
Two men carrying pistols (speaking spanish)
- Your spanish is excellent, sir
- Thank you
- I gotta go!
- Sir?
Americans...
The boss wants him alive!
She's returned.
Get ready to intervene.
- Yes
- Commander Acheson, two armed men are chasing the American from yesterday.
Shots have been fired.  Request permission to intervene.
Do you still have Elise?
We still have a visual on Elise Ward, but the American is in imminent danger.
You mean the mathematics teacher from Wisconsin?
I'd say not our mandate.
Sir, this man is in real peril.
This is exactly why she chose him, to distract us.
Stay with her
Do not move unless she moves.
Am I making myself crystal clear?
Sir, they will kill him.
Not our mandate.
- Look at that man!
- What the hell?
Center, send someone to the market!
There is a nut trying to kill himself.
American, I bet.
Stop, stop!
Do not jump!
- I'm so sorry
- Asshole!
I'm sorry!
- Stop him
- I'm sorry, sorry!
- Answer the phone.
- Yes, sir.
- I think you need it more than I.
- "Thank you" (speaking spanish)
"You're welcome" (speaking spanish)
Smoke?
No?
- Now, you wish to report a murder?
- No.
Some people tried to kill me
I was told you are reporting a murder.
Attempted murder.
- That's not so serious.
- No, not when you downgrade it from murder.
But when you upgrade it from room
service, it's quite serious.
- So is assaulting a Police Officer.
- That was an accident.
The Officer feels differently.
...With all due respect, sir
...I think maybe I should be talking with someone
...Someone not Italian.
- Like the Embassy, or Interpol.
- Interpol?
I'm an American citizen.
- What does that mean?
- I do not know.
But I was involved in something here and no offense,
this is not a local issue.
What is it you think you're involved in?
It all started when I met a woman
on the train from Paris
- This already good!
- No, no.
She took me to her hotel.
- Ah, wonderful!
- No, no.
...she's involved with another man, I think she's in love...
- Sorry to hear that
- I know
...Anyway
This man, whatever his story is.
Some people are obviously trying to kill him.
- How do you know this?
- Because they tried to kill me.
- They tried to kill you?
- Yes!
Because they must have thought that I was him.
- I like you Mr. Tupelo
- I like you too, sir
But surely you understand how strange this all sounds.
Come with me
Where are you taking me?
Oh!  You're going to lock me in there?
Please don't do this.
Sir, I've done nothing wrong
- Please!
- It's only until I check some facts
Hi.
Your facts checked out.
We have to leave.
- You're not safe here
- I don't understand
This has to look right.
Come on
The man you're talking about is
called Alexander Pierce
...who stole big money from a gangster.
They came to Venice to find him
They think you are him
They placed a... how do you say... bounty on your head.
That's why you're not safe.
Wait here for a moment
You've come to buy a key?
Brand new bills, I appreciate it
You think we cheat you?
Of course not, I just enjoy counting
Well, gentlemen, Alexander Pierce is all yours.
Do not shoot him!
I think we lost them!
I'd really like to take these off!
We have to wait until we get to open waters
It suits you perfectly, sir
You have a wonderful figure.
- You think it's a little loose?
- No, it's of the utmost magnificence
Fourteen red, bet made.
Wager, sir?
Forty-two red
- They're back.
- Yeah, bring them in.
- I'll come back tomorrow?
- No, no, no, stay.
We tried everything, sir
- But he got away.
- So I heard, so I heard.
They're referring to the young man who
stole $2.3 billion dollars from me.
You know, I worked very hard for years so I wouldn't have to
do the dirty work any more. No more chasing traitors
...No more killing
Now I employ people
to do those things for me
Except that you don't!
- Does it look alright?
- Yes!
- Like always.
- What's always?
Very good.
Yes, I think it looks alright!
Huh, so that's how you pick a lock.
How do you know how to do that?
Where's the owner of this boat? Bottom of a canal?
Sitting at a cafe with a pocketful of Euros
Why is this happening?
Why is everyone trying to kill me?
Because I kissed you.
Do I look that much like him?
I am sorry I got you involved in all this.
Why are you involved in all this?
- Because I'm in love with him.
- Really? I'm not.
...Seriously, help me understand why?
I honestly didn't think he would let it go this far.
I didn't think he would let Shaw get to you.
Shaw - that's the man who Pierce stole from?
Reginald Shaw. Alexander used to be his private banker.
- I thought he was Russian or something like that.
- He surrounds himself with the Russians.
But he's as English as Alex and I.
Give me your hand
Now he owns most of the casinos and brothels
from here to Novus Brusk
Once, he bragged to Alexander that he had every man killed
his wife had slept with before she met him.
And when he found out how many there had been... he killed her too.
There you are.
What made Pierce think he could take on a guy like that?
It's just who he is.
Could you ever feel like that about someone like me?
I don't regret it, you know. Kissing you.
I have to go check the, umm... the thing...
Where are we going?
The airport?
- Where are we going?
- You'll see.
Tie us up, would you?
I wish we'd met in another life, Frank.
Take the next flight back to America,
you'll find what you need in the bag.
Be safe.
But I'm in love with you...
Agent Elise Clifton-Ward.
Identification number "M, F, S, 98495, G"
Clearance Authorization Approved
Well, you've certainly blown your cover now.
I'm ready to give you Pierce.
You're ready to give me Pierce?
Well that's interesting.
So you're aren't here to beg me to lift your suspension?
You've actually come to do your job?
Allow me to ask.
Why now?
You live with a man for an entire year.
During which time, we don't get one single useable photograph.
Now you're ready to give him up?
It's because of that tourist, isn't it?
I want to put an end to this
before someone gets killed.
...I wish I could understand your choice in men.
...The fugitive thief?
Well, that's exciting, perhaps
But a school teacher from Wisconsin?
Who'd have thought your tastes were so provincial?
- Do you want Pierce or not?
- Yes
I'm meeting him at a ball. Tonight.
You know you'll have to wear a wire?
Hello Madam
"She's moving toward the southeast corner"
Where've you been?
I thought you'd never get here.
Really?
"So tell me"
Is that our man?
How could you be so sure I was coming?
I just knew it.
Fate wouldn't bring me to an evening like this with no reason.
As soon as you walked in, I knew what the reason was.
- No?
- No
"Count Philipe Organza, land owner, big reputation as a swordsman"
Well, he won't be dueling tonight.
Wait!
Alexander!
Excuse me.
It's Pierce, he's here.
He just left her an envelope.  Pull
up the footage, we have his face.
I don't bloody believe this!
Alright, get that moron out of here.
You shouldn't be -
I can't, I'm sorry.
Come on, you owe me a dance.
You shouldn't be here.
No, Elise.  This is the only
place on earth I should be.
How did you get in here?
I told the doorman, you're my wife
and I wanted to keep an eye on you.
Italians are big on that kinda thing
- Leave.
- No.
Do you like the suit?
You paid for it.
I've been thinking about your friend Pierce, and his plan.
So far, I'm thinking it hasn't worked out for him.
No?
No, take that gangster guy.
- Shaw?
- Yeah, Shaw.
I don't believe that Pierce was prepared for him
being here.  The whole chase.
Will you please leave?
You're kinda worried about me, aren't you?
Yes.
And I'm worried about you
And I'm not leaving without you
You were part of the plan.
You were useful, that's all.
Why do you think, I saw you on the
train and my heart stopped?
Leave.
This way please.
Excuse me sir, I think you've made a mista--
"Fondamenta San Giacomo 23, Tonight"
What's it say?
Ms. Ward's boarding the boat.
"It looks like they've called up her boat, what should I do?"
She may just be playing with us, let's wait.
Fondamenta San Giacomo 23, please
Okay, good.  We have the address.
I'm going to follow her on the boat.
I want snipers on all surrounding roofs
and if you get a visual on Pierce first, call.
The Commissioner wants a report.
Hello?
Let's have a little fun with him
Please?  (speaking spanish)
Who are you people?
Where are we going?
Well, I don't know, Alexander. Where are we going?
I'm not Alexander, my name's Frank Tupelo.
I'm an American citizen and I have rights
I don't care what you call yourself these days
Your name's Alexander Pierce and you have no rights
Not until you pay us 744 million pounds back taxes
Seven hundred and forty-four million?
Looks like someone else is following our target.
Reginald Shaw.
Well, this could be fun.
Alright, stay close but not too close
- And get the office to send me an interpreter.
- Right.
Yes, 744 million
You didn't think we knew about that
bank account in Liechtenstein.
I don't know what you are talking about
Listen
...You asshole.
I know everything about you.
I even know how much that face cost.
24 million wired to a Brazilian surgeon
from a numbered Swiss bank account.
I haven't been able to prove it
...But now I don't have to.
...Because I just lock you in a box in the basement
Until you tell me where the money is.
It's alright.
It's alright, Frank.
I know you're not Alexander Pierce
But you know who you are?
You're a moron.
And you're a moron that almost
ruined my ? million pound sting operation.
Twice...
So you're going to stay here until this is all over.
Please, you can't do this
I haven't done anything
I shouldn't be here.
Know what I think?
...I think that this is the one place on Earth
You really should be.
How was your night at the hotel?
She's quite something, I'm sure.
Target is about 200 yards away from destination.
- We are matching speed.
- Good.
But don't get too close.
I don't want to scare Pierce off again.
We're here.
- Go ahead.
- Thank you.
I won't be needing you any more this evening.
Magnificent.
I've never really understood the love that people devote to each other.
Money, yes. Possessions, yes.
But people are so unreliable, they sicken decay and die.
But this, this is worth dying for.
"...such good taste"
We're live.
Oh, yes, do sit down.
When are you going in?
You're welcome to stay and watch
If you can keep your mouth shut
"You know, Alexander was like a son to me"
I loved him.
That brilliant, playful, disrespectful young bastard.
I even thought he and I were two of a kind.
I took great pleasure never knowing
what the scamp would do next.
Until one day, what he did next...
didn't give me any pleasure at all.
...You know, in our quaint legal system
...When a man sleeps with my wife
...I kill him and her. Get away scot-free
...Crime of passion as it was called
But my passion extends to all the things I own
They are me, they represent me.
So if a man steals from me, I kill him
... I kill his wife, his children, his mother
...I might even throw in the family doctor
for good measure.
For he has taken from me something for
which I have paid the infinite price.
My Soul.
That's something these idiots will never understand.
He's not coming, is he?
He sent you to get the money.
So where is it?
Where's my money?
- Where is the safe?
- I don't know.
Where is the safe?
I don't know.
You don't know?
Is it behind this bookcase here?
...Or, perhaps
...This one here
- Where is the safe?
- ... I don't know, I haven't seen him si--
Please, you have to do something
Permission to fire?
Hold your fire.  I repeat, hold your fire.
Not until Pierce shows himself.
You're very beautiful, Elise.
Try to combine it with a little intelligence.
- And tell me where the safe is.
- If I knew it, I would tell you.
In my opinion she knows nothing.
You have to go in.
They're gonna kill her.
- Where's my interpreter?
- They're going to kill her.
- She can handle herself.
- She can handle herself?
She's one of us.
Expert in undercover operations.
When I sent her to Russia to find Pierce
She went dark.
...I think she could never quite decide
If she was with him, or with us.
She's a good agent
...Except that she invariably falls in love with any man
That she spends longer than a train ride with.
Commander Acheson, I'm the interpreter.
Yes, go!
If you could provide me with some context...
...She really doesn't seem
...To know where it is
"We should go"
We give it five more minutes
If Parce doesn't show -
If Pierce doesn't show, we get rid of the woman and go.
- Permission to engage?
- Negative.
- Please!
- Not one more word from you.
They won't kill her.
Pierce will come.
He has to come.
Well alright, let's do it.
No, knife.
"Engaging target"
- Negative, that is an order.
- Order the shot.
Now if you don't tell me where the safe is
I might be tempted to rearrange your face somewhat
You'll find life is not quite so giving to an ugly woman.
You really don't know, do you?
There!
Behind the medallion, there!
Open it.
There is movement in the courtyard
Pierce, I knew it
You know what, he does look a little like you
No!
Just try.
Go on, press it.
You may try one more time.
Let her go!
Oh, my God.
- You let her leave and I'll open the safe.
- Stop right there.
...Frank, what in hell?
Please Elise let me handle this
I'll say it again, let her go
I'll open the safe.
- Who the hell are you?
- I'm Alexander Pierce.
This is the man that was driving the boat
- He is not Alexander Pierce.
- Elise, please.
What the hell are you doing?
What the hell is he doing?
"Permission to engage target?"
Shut the hell up.
Alexander, is it you?  Truly?
Truly.
Show me your teeth
Alexander had crooked teeth
Stained from excessive smoking
Braces. Electronic cigarettes.
He had a higher forehead
I had a migraine for two weeks after the remodel
- You sound different
- Voice chip implant
No, no, I mean the the way you speak
Yes, that's right, Alexander was English
This man is American
I've actually gotten so used to the American accent
that I find it a tad difficult to go back
That's pathetic, this man is not Alexander Pierce
He's a tourist!
A tourist?
Someone I happened to sit next to on the train
How would a tourist
know that you killed every man your wife ever slept with?
I told him that
You told a tourist?
Why would she do that?
It's absurd.
Well, there's a simple way of finding out
- Open the safe
- I've made you a deal
...When she's gone
What are you doing?
...and I know she's safe
...Then
Well... I'll make you an even better deal
Open the safe now...
And I won't make you watch something
that you would never forget.
Open it!
I see
Now you see?
- ...Sir
- I know him, he'll come for her
I know him
He won't give her up now
"We must engage."
"Permission to engage, sir?"
Sir...
I love you
He'll come for her
He'll come for her,
he doesn't make se-
This is Chief Inspector Jones, permission granted!
Fire!
- Are you alright?
- Yes.
Agent Ward, your suspension's lifted
Thank you, sir
And your employment is terminated,
effective immediately.
Thank you, sir
"We got him, we got Alexander Pearce."
Where?
"On the vondameta, 300 meters south of your location."
So, you love me?
I do.
How do you feel about Alexander Pierce these days?
I love him too, unfortunately
I may have a solution for you
Are you with me this time?
Come on, let him up.
I'm just a tourist.
Just a tourist.
He said I might get arrested at some point
What?
But that you'd have to let me go because you have nothing on me
Who?
The man who's been sending me these texts
Texts?
And the money, of course.
So let me get this straight because I'm... a little confused
You received money from a man you've never met before?
Who sends you text messages telling you
just to show up somewhere
Well...
Not just anywhere...
Clear!
Seven hundred and fourty four million
Inspector Acheson, this operation has been officially terminated.
I'll expect your report on Monday.
- Sir, listen
- We have our money, Acheson
But we don't have Pierce.
The man is a criminal wanted in 14 countries
But what is it he did?  Really?
He stole the money from a gangster. A dead gangster.
And he has good taste in women.
I can't say I don't wish him well.
Twenty million dollars on plastic surgery...
And that's the face you choose?
- Do you not like it?
- It'll do.